Um, so, like, I could be dead in 5
years. I have no idea.
I really have no idea though.
>> Everything's a possibility, I guess.
>> [laughter]
>> Nah, bro. Try and try and look at the
brighter side.
>> Welcome to the Cat Table again in New
York.
>> Yes, sir.
>> If you don't know what the Cat Table is,
the Cat Table is your twice a week
update on everything tech related and
startups and everything in that good
nature. Because, you know, the thing is,
Jaden and I, and Ishaan as well, he has
more pedigree than us cuz he's Indian.
But, [laughter]
the thing is, we need to bring on people
that that know more about the space than
we do,
>> [laughter]
>> right? And just like are just better
than us.
>> You're literally Chinese, bro. Like,
what are you talking about?
>> Woah. I'm trying to do the intro here.
>> My bad.
>> [laughter]
>> Woah. So, we have on today, while the
Cat Table is in New York, we have on
SideShift.
>> YES, SIR.
>> I'M SO EXCITED. YES. OKAY.
>> So excited.
>> [laughter]
>> Happy to be here.
>> I know. You twist my arm, right?
>> Twist my arm.
>> May- maybe since, you know, I I think
some of the audience might know what
SideShift is, but some of the audience
doesn't, I know. Eric and Ishaan
probably I'll lob to Ishaan here. Is it
Is it UGC
mogul, perhaps? We could do on the talk
a little bit about what SideShift is.
>> Yeah, SideShift is your two-go UGC
platform. Uh like, cut me off if I'm
missing anything, but essentially
>> go-to UGC platform?
>> It's the number one It's the number one
UGC platform.
>> It's the only one I know.
>> It's the only one that I know. It's the
only one.
>> It's the only one. There's no other
ones.
>> As a UGC or as a company, you can like
post an application. You can get a lot
of jobs listing. You can
post a job listing, have a lot of
applications. You can do your entire
analytics on it, as well as payouts.
Anything else that I'm missing?
>> Yeah, I mean,
maybe I I could give a little better
intro.
>> [laughter]
>> You know, how about we first of all,
like, what are y'all's names?
>> Oh, yeah.
>> I'm Nick.
>> This is Oliver.
>> I'm Oliver, yeah.
>> I'm a co-founder. Oliver's head of
growth, founding founding team.
>> There we go.
>> And uh yeah, we've been kicking on this
for like 2 years. So, basically
>> So, what what is SideShift from a
founder's perspective?
>> The world I mean, like, bro, you hit me
with the two-go and
backpedal from there. It's the uh
world's largest UGC platform. We connect
over 900,000 creators with over a
thousand different brands ranging from
consumer apps to B2B to entertainment
and kind of everything in between.
>> Mhm.
>> Like you said, it's full stack. You can
essentially match with creators. You can
run analytics. You can track payments.
Uh you can handle all the legal tax,
1099s. Everything directly in one
platform to launch your UGC campaigns.
>> Yeah. I mean I was just say
>> That's tough.
>> Yeah. I was just going to say for
context like I literally started a
campaign. I was talking to Oliver about
it maybe a month ago and we already got
like 3,000 or 3,500 applicants within a
month. So
>> Pretty good.
>> You guys have a really large huh?
>> Do you Do you hire any yet?
>> Of course. Come on. Let's go. I think we
hired like well I'm very selective but
over like 150. So
>> Nice.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> That's a big program, man.
>> That's a big program. That's a big
program.
>> Yeah.
>> There's also a lot of opportunities for
agencies. So if like people are like
running campaigns and want to actually
form a real agency like we give you guys
big opportunity to find like brands in
the platform. So like we have a big
inbound. A lot of brands are interested
in UGC right now so we can connect them
like super easily with agencies so they
can like run their full campaign.
>> No, I mean yeah. I mean besides if like
you know it's it's coming at a good
time, right? As like the rise in UGC.
>> Right, right.
>> consumer apps that um you know started
doing very well and some also like SAS
products as well.
>> Mhm.
>> So I mean it started two years ago. What
was that moment where you looked at UGC
and you were like ah we needed to build
something for this. [laughter]
>> to be something huge, [clears throat]
right? Because UGC isn't what it was two
years ago.
>> No, you're you're you're 100% right.
That kind of goes into the intro like
origin story a little bit.
>> It's a long story.
>> It's a little bit of a long story. I'll
try to make a long story short.
Essentially we were like hacking on
another idea. It was a labor
marketplace.
It was essentially connecting like
students across different college
campuses with local bars and
restaurants.
And we scaled this thing up to like 25
different campuses and like 10,000 like
students.
>> Mhm.
effectively like what ended up happening
is we started to go viral on tech
Twitter.
>> Huh.
>> Honestly like shout out like PlayKid,
Julia Pintar. She She gave us some some
love and was like, "SideShift is the
best platform to source UGC creators.
There's a ton of college students."
>> Mhm.
>> And as soon as like she started like
firing out these like tweets, our
inbound funnel just started going crazy.
Like people were self-serve signing up
for the first time ever instead of
saying
>> Oliver
>> knocking on like local local bar and
restaurant doors. And
ever since then like we saw the power of
UGC. We started doing it ourselves. And
then we're like we got to just go full
bore into the creator economy. This is
going to be huge. And here we are today.
>> And that that was like only a year ago.
Like a year ago we made like the full
pivot in like like mid-May slash like
early June.
>> Yeah.
>> But before that like the business was
completely different. Like we were doing
like legitimate local job hiring like
>> Wow.
>> Like I don't know if you guys went to
like big colleges, but we went to
Wisconsin like Big Ten campus. And
>> Yeah.
>> most of the businesses there are like
like bars, restaurants, like coffee
shops,
>> Mhm.
>> whatever. They hire like the students on
campus. So like we're like, "Oh, this is
a brilliant idea. Like those businesses
will hire like students at Wisconsin and
then we'll like get paid from the
businesses." But like
>> Right.
>> those businesses did not want to pay
>> anything. They're also
>> very price sensitive.
>> Price sensitive local businesses are
just like hard to work with. Like
>> Also like their margins are already
thin.
>> Yeah.
>> Razor thin already. And it's like if you
can sell to those people and we did get
some good sales, you know. I think at
our peak we're doing like 1K MRR.
>> There you go.
>> After like
>> [laughter]
>> After like six months. But um
>> Yeah.
>> No, we survived long enough to realize
that there was another market that we
could build into.
>> Yeah. I mean that's something people
don't realize as well as the fact that
you just got to keep building.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You got to keep iterating as well.
>> Yeah. Pivoting is okay, man.
>> Yeah. I mean I feel like a lot of the
companies we talk to and a lot of the
startup founders we talk to
>> Everyone benefits.
>> Yeah. The best companies came were born
on a pivot, man.
>> See where the market is.
>> Slack.
>> Yeah.
>> Twitter.
>> Twitter now?
>> Instagram.
>> Ideas don't come out fully formed.
>> Exactly. Yeah. You know, they come out a
little bit deformed met her
>> Exactly.
>> [laughter]
>> And then you nurture it in the real
world.
>> That's right, bro. It's just like
content. You got to keep iterating.
>> Talk to us about yourselves. I'm
curious. So, so one by one,
>> [laughter]
>> give me your your full story if you can.
>> Yeah. And how did you guys meet and then
like how did you guys even come up with
like even the first iteration? When did
you guys decide to
>> Oh gosh. All right, I guess we got to go
way back. I'm originally from Edina,
Minnesota. Right outside the Twin
Cities.
And effectively, I grew up playing
hockey.
Always had interest interest in
entrepreneurship. My mom's an
entrepreneur. Shout out mom.
Ended up going to the University of
Wisconsin-Madison. When I was there, you
know, like most kids I wanted to join a
frat. Ended up joining a fraternity
called Phi Gamma Delta.
>> Oh.
>> Shout shout out to the boys. [laughter]
I ended up joining fall of my like
freshman year. And
essentially, I met my two other
co-founders in my PC. We all loved
entrepreneurship. We all loved like
hacking on things. We had served on some
like executive boards together. And I
guess like senior year is when we really
started to think about like what would
life be like if we didn't go into
corporate and we started our own thing.
Even though that thing didn't work for
the first year, like we had a great time
building it.
>> So, the thought was always
entrepreneurship.
>> The thought was always entrepreneurship.
I mean, I had worked in New York. I was
in private equity real estate. I was an
intern.
>> So, like I don't really know what that
is.
>> You know, I mean I was just like
underwriting
essentially these like class A
multi-family deals all day and I was
like, "Ah, I don't know if this is
really what I want to do forever." It's
what a lot of my friends were doing. I
just wanted to take a little bit of a
larger risk. And
yeah, my co-founder Kenny and I, we we
hacked away for 6 months. Then our third
co-founder joined, Drew.
>> Tell me about the first idea, the barter
system.
>> The barter system.
>> What is that?
>> We're taking it back to Mesopotamia.
>> [laughter]
>> I mean like honestly, bro. Like we uh
sat up sitting in my apartment like
senior year with Canyon.
And we're like we got to come up with
something. Like this is step one of like
building a company. And I know
everyone's like "Oh, you got to build a
company like out of like a real like
pain point. Like it's got to be like
something you wake up every day and like
be so determined to solve." And like
honestly, we just wanted to start a
company cuz we like like to build
things. And I honestly think that's fine
answer, too.
And we're like sitting there like
jamming on ideas. And one of the ideas
we like came up we we came up with was
like we were going to replace Venmo. And
we were going to bring back the barter
system. [laughter]
So like essentially like you you'd be at
the bar and your boy would like buy you
a like a $2 drink. And instead of like
giving him $2, you would give him like
your hat or like
like something like I don't know. Like
something your $15 hat.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah.
Yeah, at one point it was like an NFL
gift card for like a like a Chipotle
bowl. And then we were like, "Yeah,
these two just like don't match up in
economic value."
>> So was it like was it like a software?
Like how did it work?
>> Yeah, I don't think you got that far.
>> Oh, this is just like conversation.
Yeah.
>> I mean this was this was like we were
like drawing out like wire frames on a
whiteboard. And we were like, "Wait,
wait, this is stupid.
Do something else." [clears throat]
Um but yeah, I think like I should
probably weave in how I met Oliver.
Oliver joined our fraternity second
semester. He was a spring bid. And uh
Uh
like
>> [laughter]
>> You know what's funny? On the walk over
here, I I just assumed. I was like, "Yo,
Ishaan, I feel like they're just like
frat bros."
>> And I was like, "No, I don't think so."
>> [laughter]
>> I I think I think I think I said
yesterday I was like, "I think they're
just two frat guys."
>> Yeah, low-key.
>> Yeah, and it's a part like a vital part
of the origin story.
>> I mean it is, bro. That's like how we
all met each other. That's how we became
friends.
>> I mean like the the whole founding team
had like some executive position at
at our frat. Like he was like secretary.
Yeah.
>> DJ it was like DJ I was like secretary.
chairs he was like Rex Zach
Rush chair Canyon was like
if you're not getting with a brother or
if you're not a brother
get the [ __ ] out of here.
>> [laughter]
>> Are you guys in frats?
>> No no I went to USC for like a semester.
>> It's not really like that honestly
that's just like
>> Some of the USC guys were very
>> [laughter]
>> We were pretty chill we were like
>> I remember at Berkeley they
>> They were like that too.
>> They were like that at my school too at
my school
>> Yeah that's just like OD to be like
that. Most I think that's actually like
a stigma. Most like frat guys are
actually pretty
>> Yeah it is it is wholesome.
>> Yeah a lot of smart guys there.
>> Also we haven't talked about Oliver.
Oliver please introduce yourself.
>> Okay guys I'm Oliver. Thanks for having
me. I appreciate it. Um originally from
Chicago so also a mid Midwest guy like
Nick. And
Oh
where do I start?
>> have a bone over that being from the
Midwest?
>> No not really.
>> Minnesota's like kind of weird like I'm
>> Chicago Chicago's most like mid-tier
city.
>> [laughter]
>> Chicago doesn't even know about Chicago.
>> Dude like compared to New York and LA
>> Okay okay.
>> You want to hear Derrick Rose and he's
like a New York knicks fan.
>> I'm a Derrick Rose fan bro.
>> New York is pretty good. We've been here
for like
>> I mean New York is sweet but like
Chicago's like one of the most beautiful
major cities.
>> it's nicer there the city planning is
amazing.
>> Yeah I'mma take Minneapolis over
Chicago.
>> Stop. You've never actually been to
>> Um no no from Chicago. Honestly like
I've been kind of like a a hustler my
entire life in some like fashion. I
don't think I was like the best like I
was never like the best at school. I
think I was like not like super
academically inclined.
>> History major.
>> Yeah yeah I skated my way through
through Madison. I'm like kind of I
guess I'm like somewhat smart but I I
definitely like had more passion more
interest in like making money and like
selling things. Like honestly that was
always kind of an interest of mine. I do
most of our sales just like kind of
excites me.
>> That was awesome.
>> So like I I I like a a bunch of like
random businesses like I was like, you
know, drop shipper, I was like sold
Supreme, big sneaker reseller.
I had a few like gray
>> So you have the Yeezy Turtle Doves.
>> Of course. What did you learn that from
[clears throat] startups?
>> For sure. Yeah, the sneaker the sneaker
pipeline to like app game is insane.
>> Yeah, all the [ __ ] guys like
>> It's a bunch of There's a bunch of
companies
>> You always noticed there are there like
sneaker resellers or Roblox game
developers?
>> Yeah, that's also a good hustle.
>> That's signal. That's high signal VCs.
>> Yeah, that's just high signal right
there. But yeah.
>> But um yeah, I went to went to Madison.
Wasn't actually was going to go play
basketball in college, but then
>> No way.
>> I was a COVID graduate of high school,
so like didn't want to go like, you
know, maybe I wouldn't have a season, so
I went to Madison. I thought frats were
dumb, so I didn't join them first
semester, and then I was like I met Nick
and all the like all my roommate and
like everyone all my friends that I'd
made they were like you should come
join.
Nick low-key rushed me, honestly.
>> [laughter]
>> I recruited him twice now.
>> I thought he was so weird because
his like his like in his profile picture
on messages was like him in a suit. And
I was like Who's this like serious dude?
>> [laughter]
>> I thought he was like corporate.
Yeah, yeah, legit Patrick Bateman photo.
But then he like showed me the house. I
was like this guy this guy seems chill.
But we didn't really become friends
>> showed up in the middle of the winter to
the house. I'll never forget you. I
think you were wearing the shorts with
the Tims. I was like
>> I was wearing shorts with Tims.
>> Shorts with Tims in like
>> No, I was rocking Tims.
>> In like 20-degree weather, bro. Is that
like a Chicago thing?
>> No.
>> [laughter]
>> I was just rocking Tims.
>> No, but shorts with Tims.
>> Shorts and shorts.
>> How long were the socks? Yeah, and where
were the socks? Like what
>> How long were the socks? Yeah, the Nike
Elites on, bro. The Nike Elites on.
[laughter]
>> The neon green ones?
>> Exactly. Green ones, bro. Pulled all the
way up.
>> Oh, no. I'm crying.
>> Yeah, I feel like we didn't really
become like close friends until like
maybe second semester sophomore year,
like junior year.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> Um and then
towards like I guess the end of senior
year I started I was seeing what like
Nick and Canyon were doing. They were
like starting like Satch and V1, I
guess, like the local job market. And I
was just like did not want to go into
the corporate world. Like didn't
honestly have many leads to be honest.
>> But but ended up telling me he had
leads, bro, to like try and get a better
job offer.
>> [laughter]
>> Even though we were paying him like
nothing.
>> No, we dude, we were
>> He's like, "I just got another offer, so
we're going to have to renegotiate."
>> going to do something
>> You got to larp, bro. You got to larp.
But like, you can't larp when there's
like nothing to larp toward.
>> [laughter]
>> Dude, I actually was like joking. I
didn't think you were going to take it
seriously, but you were like, "What?"
>> Like, dude, what are we going to do?
>> I'm going to rip [laughter] up the term
sheet.
>> But uh
I remember I told uh Nick and Canyon and
I had like one like super day for like a
real estate finance job that like
sounded good on paper. And I like drove
down to Chicago for like a super day. It
was like 4-hour interview. And I told
like them before I was like, "All right,
if I if I get this job, like I'm going
to take it. But if I don't, I'm all in
and I'm like ready to ride until like
the wheels fall off." kind of thing.
Um and I think like
Yeah, I mean, I didn't get it obviously
and I was kind of like fired up. I
remember
>> Quickest quickest interview ever.
>> [laughter]
>> No, I actually did well.
>> I I didn't do that well.
>> I I didn't even have any business being
in that room. I didn't even major in
real estate. I majored in history.
>> [laughter]
>> I don't know [ __ ] about real estate.
>> Um but that's actually Canyon when I got
rejected. I was like, "Dude, I'm all in.
Like, let's let's ride."
>> And then let's ride.
>> You should have told them that in the
middle of your you stood up and you're
like, "This isn't right." And you're
like,
>> Well, I mean, at the time, bro, like my
brain was so like scrambled from all the
partying for like a couple years that
like I was just trying to get a job,
like,
>> [laughter]
>> you know?
>> Madison's seems like a fun school.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it was a good time.
>> It's a really good school.
>> This could be totally incorrect, so if
I'm wrong, we can cut this, but it did
Was Nick Daniel from Series involved in
your guys' first round? Like, your your
pre-seed [laughter] or like your dorm
room seed?
>> You could tell us the truth.
>> It is Okay, I saw it somewhere online
like a long time ago. And I was like,
"What the fuck?"
>> All right, so like
>> That was a good pull. I'm glad I brought
that up.
>> That is a good pull. So, we had Okay,
this is I guess I'll try to make this
quick.
>> Yeah, we want to
>> Yeah, yeah. No, I Yeah, it's it is true,
actually. So, essentially
like
September 2023,
like right when Canyon and I were like
launching SideShift, a younger kid in
our fraternity is from Connecticut
hooked us up with like this fund out of
Yale. It's called Bullmont. It was run
by Albert Yang. Shout out to Albert.
Actually like first one of the first
believers in side shift.
Uh even like when we had nothing he just
believed in me and Canyon. And um
Nathaniel was also like part of the that
fund as well. I'm pretty sure it was
just like they had like a pool of like
they had like a fund of like 500k from
like wealthy alumni donors.
And essentially like we went through
this like long interview process like
couple interviews worth and uh we ended
up like getting a $10,000 like
investment from them which is actually
was like huge for us at the time.
You know because like that actually
paved a lot of the uh the Fiverr cost
that we were
>> [laughter]
>> that we were spending cuz we weren't
technical and we had no CTO. We didn't
have Drew at this point. So like that
went all like to Fiverr credits and then
it was honestly a a huge
uh like catalyst for for getting our
first product out.
>> Wasn't Albert also like at the end
wasn't he like all right [ __ ] it I'm
just going to write you a check?
>> I mean yeah yeah yeah. I mean Albert was
like
he was he was the total boy and like I
don't think he really believed in like
that actual business but he was like I
really just like messed with you guys.
Like I I think there's something here. I
don't know if this is the idea but I'm
going to write you this like $10,000
check.
Shout out to Albert.
>> Yeah shout shout out to Albert.
>> Uh it was on a it was on an uncap safe
for uh it was a yeah yeah I don't want
to get too much into
>> [laughter]
>> Probably a good investment for Albert
though. Hey.
>> Yeah yeah yeah. It was a it was a great
inves- it was a great investment for
Albert.
>> Yeah. I I have a another question
concerning like product a a little bit
cuz in the earlier part you guys
mentioned being full stack and then you
mentioned 1099s. I'm curious how do you
guys get most of your product ideas?
Like
kind of some of the things you you were
saying it sounded like you guys are
pretty close to the users. Like that
sounds like something that a user would
want. So I'm curious how you guys get
>> I think the best way anyone can ever get
like
new features to launch is by talking to
their customers. It's something we
stress like incredibly hard at like on
our team is just talk to your customers.
If you have nothing to do, just talk to
your customers. Like if you ever find a
moment where you're not doing something
productive, just go to a Slack channel,
go to a like a text message, go to
email, and just text a customer that you
haven't talked to in a while and say,
"Hey, how's everything going?" That's
literally it.
Most often than not, you'll find that
something that's wrong, a bug that we
need to fix, or something that we could
add that make their life a lot easier.
And having like a really close touch
with your customers allows you to
iterate on the product which is 10 times
better, I think.
Um and like for example, like randomly I
decided to set up customer calls with
like to all of our top customers the
past 2 weeks and just like 30 minutes,
just like, "What do you got for me? Like
what sucks? What's great? Like how can
we make the product better? How can we
help you scale?" Um and like, you know,
that's how you you you find things that
you'll never found if you don't do that.
>> Right, right. I will say that like one
thing about us is we have like really
close relationships with like almost all
of our customers. I mean, we have
damn near, I think last time I checked,
900 like active subscribers at this
point. And essentially, every single one
like has had some sort of call or some
sort of like touch point with myself,
Oliver, Canyon, DJ, Jayden, uh like all
these like all of the members of our
team.
And it just like allows us to build
these like personal relationships with
them. So if they ever like encounter any
bugs, any issues, like they'll just text
like one of us directly. And like we're
kind of Johnny-on-the-spot for getting
it done.
>> Yeah, that's pretty good. One thing
that's actually like starting to become
a little bit of a challenge as we scale
is like being able to like
just figure out how to handle all these
like new customers because I used to
like give out my number to like
>> Yeah.
>> pretty much [laughter] everyone. Like
text me anytime. And I still do that
with this young man.
>> Yeah, thank you, bro. Yeah.
>> Like he text me at like like 11:00 on
Tuesday.
>> Okay, but
>> And I was like I was like I I was I was
like 2 minutes before I slept, I was
like, "All right, I got to text Oliver."
And then immediately text me back. And I
was like
>> high signal. I was like, "Dude, it's
like night time."
>> I text you in the morning, dude. It's
fine.
>> I was tapped in.
>> Yeah, he's like totally coffee.
>> I was like in my bed on my computer
like, "All right."
It was yeah, set up a call for the next
day. And that stuff happens a lot. And
that's something like we have to figure
out as we like really start to scale,
like how to build a team that's able to
handle, you know, all the
a product and a team that's able to
handle all the like the inquiries that
come from customers at any time of the
day. Um so that's something that we have
to navigate, which I think will be fun.
>> Oh, dope.
>> I was going to talk about the future of
UGC.
>> Yeah. So I think what's happening right
now, like and we'll get into it like AI
UGC later. My biggest question is like
how do you see UGC changing over time?
Like people talk about AI, but it
doesn't have to be AI UGC. It could be
influencer partnerships, it could be
paid ads. A lot of people are doing paid
ads now.
>> Yeah.
>> Um how are you guys going to navigate
that like change? Cuz obviously it's
going to change, right?
>> Dude, the one thing I'll say about Side
Shift is we are the best like pivoters
and adapters on earth. Like we've
already done it once and like as UGC
continues to change like we're just
going to keep adapting. We're like we're
a very open-minded team. Like we know
what's going on in the market. Like we
have a very close pulse on everything
and like as we see things start to
change like we will double down on like
what's working. We'll kill what's not
working like really quickly. And to
answer your question about like the
future of UGC and like where we see it
going, I think that the average consumer
is getting a lot smarter. Therefore, I
think like the traditional like hook and
demo like carousel [ __ ] like doesn't
really convert anymore. You need like
these really like compelling talking
head narrative videos that like really
pull a user in and I think that this
huge push with new media is driving a
lot of that. And that's like what we
focus on for our own internal program.
Honestly, like we have about 100
creators. The format that we push the
hardest is some sort of like talking
head talking style.
Hardest to do, but the conversions are
the highest if you can nail it if you
can nail it, right? And I also think
that organic UGC is just like one pillar
of growth that you should be doing. And
like even I like even we're saying that,
we're trying to go into like paid ads,
influencer. We want to own the entire
kind of like stack of the or the supply
chain of the creator economy. And like
UGC is just our wedge and now like we're
starting to eat up kind of like other
facets of said supply chain.
>> Yeah.
>> Also, I'll add to that and say like the
way I think of UGC is that like the
centerfold of like any short-form
creative testing. So, it's like the
cheapest way to get any sort of, you
know, iterative testing. So, like I can
like every brand needs to win on
short-form in some capacity in today's
era. So, like if I can get it like, you
know, 60 videos from one creator at
like, you know, 10, 20 dollars a post or
whatever the the the comp is before
bonuses. Like I'm like you you're not
going to get any sort of testing that
that cheap anywhere else, right? So,
what I can do is I can take those 60
videos, find the videos that perform the
best. That then informs my paid ad
strategy, right? Cuz I can either put
spark spend behind that or put a meta
partnership ad behind that if it's on if
it's on IG.
>> Right.
>> Um and then that will also inform what I
can do if I want to do influencer,
right? Cuz like I can take the same
creative, I can take the same format
that worked from that like initial 60
testing, and then, you know, put spend
towards influencer if that's something I
want to go into. So, like I think like
UGC will always be like even if like it
gets more competitive, which it
obviously will be and it already has
been as we've seen for the past like
year. Like I think it'll always be like
a great like expenditure for a business
to like test
how I can like, you know, build winning
creatives. Cuz everyone's going to need
winning creatives. The whole world's
turning towards short-form. So, like I
think it's kind of just at the
centerfold, and it will be like for the
next like
for the next for however long, but uh
>> forever.
>> Yeah. But as Nick said like like we
don't necessarily know what's going to
happen in the future. I think part of
the business that is a little bit tricky
is that we're very platform-dependent.
So, we depend on Instagram and TikTok
and and their algorithms and
>> I will say that
>> one caveat to that is like we have this
marketplace of like skilled labor that
wants to earn online, right? Maybe it's
not content forever, maybe it's
something else. You know, it's just like
harnessing like almost like a million
people who are like hungry to earn
online in some capacity is like
>> Yeah.
>> definitely a like something we we know
that we do have.
>> Yeah, and going into that actually, you
guys both kind of alluded to in your
answers. I'm curious if
and these things are always in influx
like you mentioned, but in five years
kind of what is the vision for Sideshift
or like if if you scale ideally, kind of
what does the ideal version of SideShift
look like? What's the ideal version?
>> you're going to say. I don't know what
you're [laughter] going to say, but I
want to hear what you're going to
>> What I like to say is that I don't think
in like five-year timelines. I couldn't
even like begin to give you an example
because like
Yeah, our business model has changed
every month or two months since the
inception of SideShift or at least since
like the pivot to the creator economy.
Um so like I could be dead in five
years. I have no idea.
I really have no idea though.
>> Everything's a possibility, I guess.
>> [laughter]
>> Come on, bro. Try to try to look at the
brighter side.
>> I mean, that is looking at the bright
side. I'm very happy to be alive.
>> [laughter]
>> You know what? No, I think that's like a
That's not a bad man. It's like wake up
every day like at least I'm not dead.
>> I mean, I I think like long-term goal is
to try and
>> [laughter]
>> To try and actually like paint the
picture, I think one of the long-term
goals that we have is like we want 100
million people earning on SideShift,
whether that is content, whether that's
a variety of other different things that
they could do. Maybe like you know, your
For You like you have your For You page
essentially on SideShift for creators
right now and it's all these different
like content gig opportunities. You
know, maybe like you open up your For
You page in another part of the world
and it's like a different type of like
earning opportunity online. Just like
we're trying to essentially change the
way that people are earning in like the
post-W-2 economy.
>> Right. Yeah.
>> Makes sense.
>> I think that's a that's a good answer.
And I would say a closer goal like in
the next like year or six months would
be just consistently starting to own as
Nick said a second ago like the entire
like
creator economy like SideShift
>> value chain
>> value chain. Yeah, like we were building
out this discover page, which is like
been really successful so far where
brands that come inbound to SideShift
can hire creators, they can hire
campaign managers, they can hire
agencies, they can hire clipping
platforms, and soon they'll be able to
hire influencers, media buyers, you
know, all this other stuff that will
allow them to just allow us to be kind
of at the forefront of all sorts of
things distribution. Um a little bit
like a referral marketplace.
>> Yeah.
>> So or we're going to
pivot into uh defense tech.
>> That'll be on there.
>> Shout out Kyle Kuzma.
>> We were selling selling GP news.
>> He said he was going to be on the couch
table.
>> He said he was going to be
>> He said he was [clears throat] going to
be on the couch table.
>> He hasn't introduced me.
>> Yeah, Kyle Kuzma.
>> [laughter]
>> It's a big if.
>> We shot him a DM on Twitter.
>> We like just we replied. We had
>> I like
>> I like quote tweeted something of his
and I was like, "Whatever, bro. I don't
even want you on our podcast anyways."
>> And he replied to my tweet saying,
"Let's do it." And I was like, "Oh
shit."
>> [laughter]
>> And we all responded in unison.
>> You got to follow up.
>> Then he went on TV the next day.
>> [laughter]
>> I was like, "LA Laker champion?"
Kyle Kuzma.
>> No, he's your champion.
>> He's actually got a cool little phone. I
was watching his video last night.
>> He's actually a Thompson.
>> he had a ghost writer, but no, like he
actually [clears throat] knows what he's
talking about. He's actually
>> I'm not surprised.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, he spent all that time in
Milwaukee. He probably just got bored.
>> [laughter]
>> I got to figure out something to do.
>> Yeah, that's a
>> Talk to us about Wisconsin.
>> So, I I think
we're three we're three California boys.
>> So
>> I feel like
>> Huh?
>> No.
>> I would say like the the a lot of the
stereotype around like some of the
non-tech schools is like, "Oh, if you
don't go to a Berkeley or Stanford, you
can never make a startup." Right? Like
you're not going to get funding as like
essentially. So, what was your process
going through like like what was the
background of like how what are people
doing in Wisconsin?
>> It's actually a great question because I
feel like
I feel like we're one of the rare few
that made it out
It's a there's a couple other great
companies. Uh Line Leaps one of them.
Have you heard of them?
>> Oh, Line Leaps from Wisconsin?
>> Yeah, Line Leaps, Brick, and Fetch
Rewards as well. They're the biggest.
But like long story short, man, like
when you're at Wisconsin, all you're
like really armed with is like YC
Startup School, bro. And you just like
get so pill done like you're never going
to get in there. It's only Stanford.
It's only like X McKinsey. Yada yada
yada you have to be insanely technical.
And this is like pre-Vibe coding. So,
like all that is essentially very true
and what they were funding back then.
And I just remember like I was like one
day I'm just going to make it out of
here. Like we're like I promise like I'm
going to go to New York and like we're
going to make this thing huge.
>> Last chopper out of Wisconsin.
>> Literally last chopper out of Wisconsin,
bro. And I just like
I always knew the odds were just so
slim. We like applied to YC six times,
denied every single time, never an
interview.
Like absolutely just cooked. And but I
was just like, you know what? Like it's
like persistence is one of the most like
powerful things in the world. Nothing
can play take the place of persistence.
It's actually a frat quote. It's a frat
quote.
It's very true. And like every day I
just would I was I would just wake up
and I'm like, all right, we're just
going to do it today. And like I don't
>> No.
>> Maybe if we just like push the rock a
centimeter, I'm just going to get up and
do it tomorrow. Tomorrow, tomorrow.
Sisyphus style.
And you know, eventually we pushed that
rock for like 505 days, I think. And
that's like
on that 505th day is when I consider us
like finding product market fit. And you
know, I feel like, you know, that has
pushed us into
you know, I don't want to say you've
ever made it, but like I want to say
that, you know, we've definitely come a
long way. And I'm like proud to proud to
see the journey so far.
>> And I'm sure a lot of those YC companies
now are using Side Shift.
>> We have a lot of YC discounts.
>> Oh, you have a YC discount now?
>> We're always getting recommended in
BookFace. Someone was telling me that
the other day. I was actually just
texting with a YC founder, Ryan Koral.
>> With so many new brands coming on the
Side Shift, I guess what's the biggest
thing
what separates a successful UGC campaign
from those that aren't doing too well,
right?
>> Yeah, that's a great question. I would
say I mean Oliver has his own answer to
this question, but I would say like what
separates a good UGC campaign from a bad
UGC campaign
is like expectations, right? People just
set these crazy unrealistic
expectations. They see like the Poly
Market program, the Whisper Flow
program, all these like massive programs
that are doing like, you know, between
250 to 500 million views a month. And
they're like, oh, I want that. But I
want to spend a thousand dollars on like
a creator and I want them to post, you
know, a hundred videos. And if it
doesn't work, then I'm like going to
churn out from this channel. So, it's
like
>> Yeah.
>> Our expectations is number one. Number
two, I would say is like people treat
these creators as like vendors instead
of like people. And that's like the
biggest difference, I think, is whenever
I'm like running a program myself. And
like I don't do it very much anymore.
>> [laughter]
>> But But, um like I I try to meet
everyone. Like I try to like actually
like get to know them, like where
they're from. Like because they're
essentially becoming evangelists for
your product, right?
>> Yeah.
>> And you don't like want to just like
treat them as like, you know, a pay stub
at the end of the day. Like you want
these people to truly be bought into
your product, into your mission. And
that's like when you give like this
content feedback, you give all of this
like, you know, iterations. Like they
take it and they apply it and they don't
just like kind of tell you to like kick
rocks and be just like retainer
merchants, right?
>> Yeah.
>> I I agree.
>> I mean, I think like to answer your
question about like what we see in most
successful, like any of the biggest and
best performing companies on Sacheuver
programs all have like a really really
like intense and like careful
relationship with the creators. I guess
intense is the wrong word, but like
>> Intense, yeah.
>> What are you What are you doing with
with the Sacheuver people?
>> [laughter]
>> They're just like they're I I would say
maybe like they're they're intensely
like proactive with their creators. And
like they foster a great community,
which you guys have probably done part
of when you got you both worked at
Turbo, right?
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> Um that's like the the best thing we did
at Turbo. We like we'd have like
retreats. We have like
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> Like I I I remember like I wasn't like I
wasn't a coach or nothing. I was like
just like running the entire funnel, but
like I remember like I just like for
like a week, I just took calls from like
our top 50 creators. And I And then like
it's funny cuz every single one of them
had the same reaction. They're like "So,
what's what's up?" Cuz they thought they
were getting fired. And I was like I
just cuz I I actually did not give them
any purpose. I wanted them to be
surprised. I was like "I the calls we
wanted to let you know today. You're
doing a great job."
>> Yeah, actually, yeah. It's [ __ ] like
that that like [clears throat] makes
these pro- programs work really well.
>> because like if you have a absolute like
killer creator, it's going to do insane
volumes for your business. Like
if you look at look at like even not in
the app space, you look at like a brand
like Comfort for example. Like
>> Boom. Comfort.
>> Boom. All those like like, you know,
they have armies of creators that like
just get absolutely like treated like
princesses and kings because they're
doing so much of like they're doing work
that provides so much value to the
business. Like if you have a creator
that's doing 10 million views on their
account, like you should compensate them
very like well and you shouldn't have
treat them incredibly well. They're
They're part of the company. They're
>> If a creator is doing 10 million views a
month, I'm like doing their laundry,
bro.
>> Exactly, bro. Like
>> And And even like they're your best
asset right there, man.
>> Yeah, and even like people that aren't
there yet, but you see potential in them
or like they've done it before and you
know there's potential you want to like
treat them incredibly well and like
foster a really strong community. So, I
think that's like a really important
thing that people do.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, I think like a lot of like I mean
Yushana and I can speak on this, too.
>> Like a lot of UGC programs I see um
they Yeah, they they just don't
understand like there's an iteration
process where they want like the program
to be kicking off within a month. I'm
like, "You need recruitment. You need
lead up. You need warm-up time. You need
to figure out whether cuz like even in
UGC, you are technically finding PMF on
the for you page."
>> Yeah, yes, exactly.
>> We call that content market fit, man.
And like I think it takes longer than a
>> CMF. It takes like longer than a month
to honestly find and like that's where
these pro- these programs will go awry
is they'll be like two weeks in not
seeing any results and like, "Oh, this
channel sucks. It doesn't work for me."
And he's like, "Bro, you didn't even
test it."
>> Yeah. We're not doing We're not doing 25
million views a month either.
>> On a $10,000 budget?
>> Like a few million views a month.
>> CPM? He's like, "He's crazy."
>> Like month one getting a few million
views is like you're you're in the
green, in my opinion. Like I also like
if you if you want to give like people
advice or like see how like a program
should work, like
we should talk about like I think a good
mirror of this is like how Side Shift
got their program started, which was
legitimately Nick making nine videos a
day. And like I was making videos. DJ
was making videos.
>> You got to provide value early on.
No customers like nothing nine videos a
day until we got our first viral video
doubled our user base and took took
about like a month to get there and then
another month for the next viral video
and then we slowly started to build a
community of creators.
>> That's right.
>> You know like like
and also if you're a founder and you're
not technical like you should be posting
as many videos as possible per day.
You should warm up a new account. You
should post every single day.
>> yeah even like I think people should
apply like e-com principles more to
consumer apps. Like if you look at like
Shawn from Ridge or like Huddleston
Comfort or Greg from Bloom. It's like
they all preach the same message and and
our boy Brian Bloom shut up Brian.
But they all preach the same message
right and that's essentially like you
need to be just like loading your for
you pages with content. It's like the
most high leverage thing you can
actually do as a founder and especially
in this day and age man. I mean the
marketing goats are truly the drop
shippers.
>> I heard I heard a really good quote. I
think I think it's from Blake Anderson
actually.
>> Yeah it was Blake yeah.
>> about e-commerce and by like what a drop
shipping like have has the best
marketers because there's no product
mode right? Software becomes more like
that due to my voting and stuff like
that. It's becoming you could see it
literally moving
>> Distribution's the final mode man.
>> Yeah no.
>> Taste and distribution.
>> Taste.
>> Oh god I hate that word.
>> Yeah [laughter] I like that.
>> No
>> It's just cuz like we talked to like a
lot of the SF people.
>> They're just always like
>> I like it but I feel like people use it
as a replacement for words that they can
use like they use it as a catchall. It's
all on some things.
>> Sure sure sure.
>> Yeah that's fair.
>> Have y'all ever thought about having
Slash if in SF?
>> Yeah.
>> Hell
>> Hell no. I'm not going to SF.
>> [laughter]
>> I mean like shoutout like shoutout SF.
I love everyone that's there. I love all
of our customers that are in SF. I just
like I'm just a big believer in like
trying to put yourself in like the best
mental headspace possible to build a
great company. And like when you're in
SF bro and like I've been there a couple
times. Every time it I'm there, it's
like
"What's your MRR?" Like, "What are you
What's retention looking like? What's
brand NR?" Like, "What's this? What's
that?" Like, "What's your CAC? Who's on
your cap table?" It's just like it's too
tech, man. It's like
at the end of the day, like you you want
to build a a a great business, and you
want to put yourself in the best
headspace, and like sometimes that means
like kind of just like unwinding,
resetting, like going out to dinner with
friends who are in different industries.
And like that's like when you can start
to formulate new ideas, because if
everyone is like thinking the same
thing, talking about the same things,
there's no innovation happening, right?
>> I agree. I I think I think a lot of
people like they just don't know how to
have a conversation. Like I've a really
good friend in the space, um Alisha
Pham, runs a really successful like
coaching and consulting business. But
every time her and I um we get lunch, we
get dinner, we never talk about work. We
just strictly just talk about a lot of
brain rot, actually.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah. I do love that SF has a ton of
nature, man. I'm a big nature guy.
>> I will say like we you have Central
Park.
>> Dude, New York's got no parks. That's
the one thing I will say. Like it's not
like Chicago. There's a lot of parks.
>> Man, we keep bringing up Chicago, bro.
>> Chicago deep.
>> Beautiful, man.
>> We're running low on time.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Do you want to talk about
>> Yeah, you just
>> Yeah, so let's talk a little bit about
AI UGC.
I brought up earlier, but essentially
there's a lot of startups, you know, a
lot of VCs thinking that like AI UGC is
the future.
>> How do you see Sideshift playing a role
in that?
>> 100%, man. I mean, I talk I talk to a
lot of VCs who
always ask that same question. I was
like, "Where's AI UGC?" And here's like
my honest take is like I'm not anti AI
UGC by any means, right? I think there's
a couple different ways you can look at
it. And I'll start with the creator
side. I think there's a lot of people
nowadays who want to create content, but
don't necessarily want to put their face
in front of a camera. I think it's a
great opportunity for them to actually
earn online creating faceless content in
some capacity. Maybe it's like really
compelling AI like, you know, narrative
UGC type stuff. Um
the one the the one like caveat to that
is I just like we haven't seen it
convert extremely well, right? I think
that once it does start to convert well
and like we have a little bit more
conviction in conversions because views
is a vanity metric. It's all about
conversions at the end of the day. Like
I don't care that your program does
like, you know, 20 million views but
like you actually get like no users or
sales from that. Like that's not a great
metric. It's about like
how much conversion are you actually
driving? And I just like have struggled
to see that from AI UGC.
However, if it does start to convert
more heavily and this goes back to what
I was saying earlier about like us being
open-minded, it's something that we
would build into the product on either
the brand side or the creator side. I'm
a little more inclined to build it on
the creator side honestly because at the
end of the day like
that's I like I love all of our
creators. I love helping people earn
online. Like the stories that we hear
like people paying off student loans.
>> Single moms like like being able to
afford
>> This had a C-section and like emergency
C-section. She was like, "Thank god for
Side Shift I could like afford it." And
like I was editing she was like editing
her videos.
>> like that like in the hospital.
Like that's like I don't know. She was
editing the videos like in the hospital.
That's all I know. Yeah, but she was
like very fortunate that you know, she's
able to earn in like a remote setting
online like due to Side Shift. Like
stuff like that like helping people earn
money is like that's like a a net
positive for society and that's like
I think a lot of our like that's both of
our internal missions. I can speak for
the rest of the team as well.
>> I would agree.
>> Yeah, it's important.
Yeah, truly a better
>> [laughter]
>> I mean I think it's like a you know,
it's a better mindset
>> than I I think Pump That Fun just
released today like
>> I saw that bro.
>> It's called like Go Pump and it's like
it's very like Black Mirror dystopia.
It's a dare system.
Like so like they put a bounty on. So
say it's like, "Oh,
I go make out with the first influencer
you see at this party and we'll pay you
$2,000." You claim the bounty.
>> That is crazy.
>> Surely nothing could go wrong with that.
>> Yeah, it's assassinations. Like that's
nuts.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay, I don't think it's going to be
like
>> It's like that one movie with Dave
Franco.
>> Oh, a nerve?
>> Yeah, nerve.
>> [laughter]
>> I don't know, man. All I know is that we
like to build things that are like a net
positive for society at the end of the
day. Try to make a world a better place.
>> I
love Jackson.
>> Yeah. Try to make the world a better
place, then
>> Everything will come. You're you're in
the right.
>> Nice.
>> Anything else you want to say to the
people?
>> Yeah, I guess some last things. We've
got a pretty interesting founding story
that we're about to launch a documentary
on, so stay tuned. Um also, we've got a
head of
>> new media who's like right here filming
us.
>> He's just been Shoutout Squill.
>> Shoutout Squill.
>> Launching a lot of really cool content
on YouTube, so like
Tap into our YouTube, our Twitter. We've
got some fun things coming.
>> Where can you find the documentary?
>> Yeah. Uh it'll be on YouTube. It'll be
on the SideShift YouTube channel.
Probably do some shorts on like X and
Instagram and TikTok and whatnot.
>> We'll be sat.
>> That's right. And if you want to get
into UGC, if you want to grow your
consumer app, your e-comm product, check
out SideShift. Use code
cap for 25% off for the first month,
first time users only.
>> Is that a Is that a thing?
>> Yeah, we're going to make it right now.
Make it
>> [laughter]
>> Yes.
>> Take a gander at that.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, that's been the Cap Table guys.
That has been, you know, SideShift.
Thanks so much for coming on.
>> You can catch us on
YouTube, X, TikTok, Instagram, Yelp,
GitHub, Patreon, Google,
>> Are we on Discord?
>> Discord,
>> Pinterest,
>> Pinterest.
>> Guys, you're everywhere.
>> Wow.
>> Spotify,
>> How do I say that?
>> [laughter]
>> Xiao Hong Shu as well.
>> What is that?
>> [ __ ] is that?
>> That's the Chinese Red Note.
>> Red Note.
>> Yeah, [laughter] lemonade. Lemonade.
>> Triller.
>> Triller, T-Series.
>> Musically.
>> All right, bye guys.
>> Peace.